Violeta Sol Arias Hours

Salta - Salta, Argentina

(+54) 9 3875377584

violehours@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/violetasolariashours

GitHub: https://github.com/VioleHours

Porfolio: https://violetahours.vercel.app/

TECH SKILLS: Javascript, Typescript, Python, PHP

FRONT-END: HTML5, Css3, ReactJs, ReduxJs, NextJs, TailwindCss, Angular, Bootstrap, Sass,

Zustand, React Native, Astro

Frontend Developer

BACK-END: NodeJs, Express, Sequelize

BASE DE DATOS: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase

CMS: WordPress, WooCommerce, Elementor,

HERRAMIENTAS: Git/GitHub, VSCode, VisualStudio, Slack, Trello, Jira, Figma AGILE: Scrum

WHOIAM

I am a Frontend Web Developer and UX/UI Designer with a background in Audiovisual Production and Fashion Design. I have experience in creating attractive and functional user interfaces. My focus is on using modern technologies to develop intuitive and high-performance web experiences. With skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and various frameworks such as React, Redux, and Next.js, I am committed to creating quality web applications that meet the highest standards of usability and design. I also have experience with agile methodologies and GIT. I have worked on both individual and group projects, which has helped me develop soft skills such as good communication, teamwork, adaptability, and problem-solving.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE.

Frontend Web Developer Freelance Part-time

Apr 2024 - Present

- Collaborated with various clients in designing and developing modern and responsive user interfaces (UI).
- Redesigned websites with UX/UI design included.
- Utilized technologies such as React.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, and Zustand to create intuitive and attractive user experiences.
- Focused on implementing responsive and accessible design to ensure maximum compatibility with different devices and browsers.
- Efficiently managed application state and maintained clean and modular code.

Frontend Developer DASCalendar · Part-time

Oct 2023 - Mar 2024

- Design and development of a responsive and visually attractive website, ensuring an intuitive and pleasant user experience.
- Leadership as Scrum Master/Product Owner, facilitating meetings and ensuring effective implementation of agile methodologies.
- Team collaboration with a focus on frontend development using React, TypeScript, and Tailwind CSS.

Odoo Developer InkuA · Internship

May 2023 - Oct 2023

- Development of websites for NGOs and Odoo updates research for websites.
- Continuous research and updates to enhance website usability and functionality.
- Implementation of custom solutions in Odoo to optimize internal processes and improve efficiency.
- Active participation in meetings and brainstorming sessions to generate new strategies and innovative approaches.

Full Stack Teaching Assistant Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023

- Coordinating a group of students to achieve integration into the study team.
- Assisting in exercise resolution and promoting group collaboration (Pair Programming).
- Proposing ideas for improving Bootcamp processes.

Camera Assistant Catholic University of Salta

Nov 2018 - Mar 2020

- Responsible for the proper maintenance of the camera during filming.
- Operation of television studio cameras for the courses of Broadcasting and Production and Direction for Radio and Television.

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

- UX/UI Design. Codo a Codo. 198 hours of theoretical-practical training. Aug 2023 Dec 2023.
- Full Stack Web Developer. Henry Bootcamp. 800 hours of theoretical-practical training. Oct 2022- Jul. 2023.
- Bachelor's Degree in Image and Sound. Catholic University of Salta. 19/50 approved subjects. 2018-2020

ADDITIONAL EDUCATION

- Fashion Design/Personal Image Consulting. Roberto Piazza Salta High Fashion and Comprehensive Beauty Institute. 2021-2022
- Production and Direction for Radio and Television. Catholic University of Salta. 2019-2020

LANGUAGES

- Spanish Native.
- English B2 Intermediate.

PROJECTS

Frontend Web Developer / Web Designer – Agroservice

May 2024 - Jun 2024

Freelance Experience. Asocaresa

Developed a web and mobile application designed to directly connect agricultural producers with e-commerce. The project aims to eliminate unnecessary intermediaries, allowing farmers to manage the sale of their products more efficiently and profitably.

Frontend: Vite, Chakra UI, JavaScript, React.

Full Stack Web Developer - PF e-latam

Jun 2022 - Jul 2023

Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp

Our project is an innovative e-commerce platform designed specifically for the dynamic and vibrant Latin American market. This platform serves as a virtual marketplace where administrators oversee business operations, while users interact with a wide range of products, reviews, and ratings. Users are free to explore an extensive catalog of products and make informed purchasing decisions.

Front: React, ReduxToolkit, Css, Vite Back: NodeJs, Express. Database: PostgreSQL y Sequelize.

Full Stack Web Developer - Countries Pl

Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp (Individual Project)

In this project, I developed a SPA (Single Page Application) about countries and activities which can be created, assigned, and deleted. It also includes combined filters, pagination, and controlled forms, among other features.

Front: React, Redux, Css Back: NodeJs, Express Database: PostgreSQL y Sequelize